I'm a visual artist,
انا فنانة تصويرية
and I'm also one of the co-founders of the Plastic Pollution Coalition.
وانا ايضاً من مؤسسي تحالف التلوث بالمواد البلاستيكية
I've been working with plastic bags,
وكنت اعمل بواسطة الاكياس البلاستيكية
which I cut up and sew back together as my primary material for my artwork
حيث اقوم بقص بعضها .. وتجميعه .. وهي موادي الاولية لعملي الفني
for the last 20 years.
في ال20 سنة التي مضت
I turn them into two and three-dimensional pieces
واستخدمهم لصناعة قطع فنية ومجسمات ثنائية ...
and sculptures and installations.
وثلاثية الابعاد
Upon working with the plastic, after about the first eight years,
بعد ان بدأت العمل بالمواد البلاستيكية .. لاحظت انه بعد 8 سنوات
some of my work started to fissure
بعض أعمالي بدأت بالتفتت
and break down into smaller little bits of plastic.
الى قطع صغيرة جداً ,, من البلاستيك
And I thought, "Great.
فقلت لنفسي .. هذا شيءُ رائع
It's ephemeral just like us."
انها فانية .. مثلنا نحن
Upon educating myself a little further about plastics,
ولكن بعد ان تعمقت أكثر فيما يخص البلاستيك
I actually realized this was a bad thing.
أيقنت ان هذا أمرٌ سيء
It's a bad thing that plastic breaks down into smaller little bits,
لأن البلاستيك .. عندما تتفتت الى اقطع أصغر
because it's always still plastic.
فإنها تبقى بلاستيك ! ( لا تتحلل )
And what we're finding
والذي نراه
is that a lot of it is in the marine environment.
بكثرة في البيئات البحرية .. هو نتاج ذلك التفتت
I then, in the last few years,
ومن ثم وفي الاعوام اللاحقة
learned about the Pacific garbage patch and the gyre.
تعرفت على مكبات ومجمعات النفايات في المحيطات
And my initial reaction --
وكان ردة فعلي المباشرة هي ..
and I think this is a lot of people's first reaction
واعتقد انها مشابهة للعديد منا
to learning about it --
والتي رأيتها عادة ..
is, "Oh my God!
هي " ياإلهي ..
We've got to go out there and clean this thing up."
علينا ان نخرج كل تلك النفايات من هنا "
So I actually developed a proposal
وقد قمت بالفعل بإستحداث حملة
to go out with a cargo ship
وخرجت بواسطة سفينة شحن
and two decommissioned fishing trawlers,
وسفينتي قطر لاصطياد الاسماك
a crane, a chipping machine
ورافعة .. وجهاز سحب
and a cold-molding machine.
وجهاز صهر على البارد
And my intention was to go out to the gyre,
بنية ان اقوم بتنظيف تلك المكبات
raise awareness about this issue
ولكي أرفع الوعي بخصوص تلك القضية
and begin to pick up the plastic,
وللبدء فعلاً برفع تلك النفايات البلاستيكية
chip it into little bits and cold mold it into bricks
وتقطيعها الى قطع صغيرة .. ومن ثم صهرها على البارد .. لتحويلها الى طابوق
that could potentially be used as building materials
يمكن استخدامه كمواد بناء
in underdeveloped communities.
في المجتمعات النامية
I began talking with people
وبدأت اتحدث للخبراء
who actually had been out to the gyre
والذين كانوا يعملون على تلك المجمعات
and were studying the plastic problem in the marine environment
والذين كانوا يدرسون مشاكل النفايات البلاستيكية في البيئات البحرية
and upon doing so,
وبعد قيامي بذلك
I realized actually that cleaning it up
ادركت ان عملية التنظيف تلك
would be a very small drop in the bucket
تبدو كإخراج قطرة من بركة سباحة يتم إمدادها بسطل مياه ممتلىء
relative to how much is being generated
هكذا كانت نسبة العمل الذي نقوم به للمخلفات التي كانت ترمى .. والتي تخرج
every day around the world,
من حياتنا اليومية من جميع انحاء العالم
and that actually I needed to back up and look at the bigger picture.
فقلت يجب ان اعيد النظر بذلك .. وعلي النظر الى الصورة الاكبر
And the bigger picture is:
والصورة الاكبر في هذه الحالة
we need to find a way to turn off the faucet.
انه لحل تلك المشكلة علينا ايقاف " صنبور " امداد المواد البلاستيكية ذاك
We need to cut the spigot
علينا ان نوقف الامداد - امداد المحيطات بها -
of single-use and disposable plastics,
عن طريق الاستخدام الفردي للمواد البلاستيكية الغير قابلة للاستخدام مرة اخرى
which are entering the marine environment every day
والتي تدخل البيئة البحرية كل يوم
on a global scale.
على نطاق الكرة الارضية
So in looking at that, I also realized that I was really angry.
وبالنظر الى هذا .. بدأت اشعر بالغضب
I wasn't just concerned about plastic
فانا لم اكن مهتمة فحسب بالبلاستيك
that you're trying to imagine out in the middle of the Pacific Ocean --
الذي يتكوم في وسط المحيط الاطلنطي
of which I have learned there are now
والذي عرفت ان هنالك اليوم
11 gyres, potentially, of plastic
11 تجمع كبير محتمل للنفايات البلاستيكية
in five major oceans in the world.
في المحيطات الخمس الكبرى حول العالم
It's not just that gyre of plastic that I'm concerned about --
كما قلت لكم .. لست مهتمة فحسب بتلك المجمعات
it's the gyre of plastic in the supermarket.
بل بتلك المجمعات في المحال التجارية
I'd go to the supermarket and all of my food is packaged in plastic.
وعندما نذهب الى المحال التجارية الكبيرة .. فان كل اغراضنا يتم تعبئتها بأكياس بلاستيكية
All of my beverages are packaged in plastic,
وكل مشاريبنا معبئة بحافظات بلاستيكية
even at the health food market.
حتى في المحال التي تبيع الأطعمة الصحية
I'm also concerned about the plastic in the refrigerator,
وانا أيضاً مهتمة بتلك الاطعمة الموجودة في الثلاجات
and I'm concerned about the plastic and the toxins that leach from plastic
وانا مهتمة بذلك التسمم الذي يتراكم في أجسادنا جراء تلك الحافظات
into us and into our bodies.
التي تحوي أطعمتنا
So I came together with a group of other people
لذا قمت مع مجموعة أخرى
who were all looking at this issue,
من الاشخاص المعنيون بنفس هذه القضية
and we created the Plastic Pollution Coalition.
بتأسيس تحالف اسمه " تحالف التلوث بالمواد البلاستيكية "
We have many initiatives that we're working on,
وكان لدينا عدة محاور لنعمل عليها
but some of them are very basic.
ولكن كان بعضها أساسيٌ جداً
One is: if 80 to 90 percent
الاهم منها .. هو ان بين %80-%90
of what we're finding in the ocean --
من المواد التي تلقى في المحيط
of the marine debris that we're finding in the ocean -- is plastic,
والتي تصل الى مجمعات النفايات الموجودة في المحيطات هي مواد بلاستيكية
then why don't we call it what it is.
لذا علينا ان نصف الامر بمسماه الحقيقي
It's plastic pollution.
انه تلوث بلاستيكي
Recycling -- everybody kind of ends their books
وإعادة التصنيع .. ذلك الامر الذي يذكر في معظم الكتب
about being sustainable and greening with the idea of recycling.
عن الاستخدام المستدام .. وعن حماية البيئة .. وعن اعادة التصنيع
You put something in a bin and you don't have to think about it again.
هو أمرٌ يتحدث عنه البعض ..دون ان يقوم بعمل جدي حياله
What is the reality of that?
ماهي فائدة ذلك على أرض الواقع ؟
In the United States, less than seven percent of our plastics are recycled.
في الولايات المتحدة الامريكية .. فقط 7% من المواد البلاستيكية يتم تدويرها
And if you really look into it,
وان نظرنا جيداً الى ذلك
particularly when it comes to plastic bottles,
فان عملية اعادة التدوير .. عندما تخص العبوات البلاستيكية
most of it is only down-cycled,
فهي يتم "تميعها "
or incinerated, or shipped to China.
أو حرقها .. او شحنها الى الصين
It is down-cycled and turned into lesser things,
ويتم تمييعها لتصبح ذات حجم اصغر فحسب
while a glass bottle can be a glass bottle again
بينما اعادة التدوير للعبوات الزجاجية .. يتم ذلك باعادة ادخالها في خط الانتاج مرة أخرى
or can be used again --
ويتم استخدامها مرة اخرى
a plastic bottle can never be a plastic bottle again.
بينما العبوة البلاستيكية .. لايمكن استخدامها مرة اخرى كعبوة بلاستيكية
So this is a big issue for us.
وهذه مشكلة كبيرة لنا
Another thing that we're looking at and asking people to think about
وهناك شيء آخر نقوم به .. وهو ان نطلب من الناس ان تضيف
is we've added a fourth R
مفهوم آخر لعملية اعادة التدوير ..
onto the front
ليصبح في المقدمة بالاضافة الى المفهوم الثلاثي لها
of the "Reduce, Reuse, Recycle," three R's,
والذي يضم .. تقليل الاستخدام .. اعادة الاستخدام .. والتدوير ..
and that is refuse.
والمفهوم الذي نريد ان نضيفه هو " رفض الاستخدام "
Whenever possible, refuse single-use and disposable plastics.
كلما كان ذلك ممكنا .. اي ان نرفض استخدام تلك المواد البلاستيكية ذات الاستعمال مرة واحدة
Alternatives exist;
في حال وجود البديل
some of them are very old-school.
وبعض تلك البدائل قديمة جداً
I myself am now collecting these cool Pyrex containers
انا اليوم اقوم باستخدام حوافظ البايركس - زجاج مقاوم للحرارة -
and using those instead of Glad and Tupperware containers
واستخدمهم بدلا من الحافظات البلاستيكية
to store food in.
لكي احفظ الغذاء فيها
And I know that I am doing a service
وانا بهذا اقدم خدمة
to myself and my family.
لنفسي ولعائلتي
It's very easy to pick up a stainless-steel bottle
ومن السهل جداً استخدام عبوة من الستالس ستيل
or a glass bottle,
او من الزجاج
if you're traveling and you've forgotten to bring your stainless-steel bottle
اثناء السفر .. وتعبئتها
and fill that up with water or filtered water,
بالماء المفلتر .. كلما فرغت تلك العبوة
versus purchasing plastic bottled water.
بدلا من شراء عبوة مياه بلاستيكية - تستعمل مرة واحدة -
I guess what I want to say to everybody here --
واعتقد انني اريد ان اقول للجميع هنا
and I know that you guys know a lot about this issue --
وانا اعلم ان الكثير منكم مهتم بهذه القضية
is that this is a huge problem in the oceans,
اريد ان اقول - ان هذه مشكلة كبيرة للمحيطات -
but this is a problem that we've created as consumers
ولكن هذه المشكلة نحن الذين قمنا باستحداثها كوننا - مستهلكون -
and we can solve.
ونحن أيضاً يمكننا حلها
We can solve this by raising awareness of the issue
عن طريق رفع الوعي بهذه المشكلة
and teaching people to choose alternatives.
وعن طريق تعليم الناس كيفية استخدام البدائل
So whenever possible, to choose alternatives
لذا كلما كان ذلك ممكنا .. إستخدموا البدائل
to single-use plastics.
بدلا من المواد البلاستيكية ذات الاستخدام الواحد
We can cut the stem -- tide the stem of this
يمكننا ان نخفض دفق تلك المواد ...
into our oceans
الى المحيط
and in doing so,
وبالقيام بذلك ..
save our oceans, save our planet, save ourselves.
يمكننا انقاذ محيطاتنا .. وكوكبنا .. وانفسنا
Thank you. (Applause)
شكرا جزيلا لكم